A Guide to the Manuscripts Vertical File, 1749 - ongoing
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Manuscripts Vertical File 1749 - ongoing
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
240
7 letter size boxes, 5 legal size boxes, 2 oversize boxes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was begun circa 1976 and continues to receive additions through donations and purchases. Many items do not have a record of their acquisition, but where donor or purchase information is available it is noted on and contained in folders.
Scope and Content
The manuscripts vertical file is an open collection containing a wide variety of unique manuscript items relating to Alexandria, Virginia residents, businesses, organizations, and history. The majority of the items within the collection are individual manuscript pages, but some books and ephemera are also included. The collection is strong in local business advertisements, stationery, and records; correspondence; legal and financial papers; memorabilia; and school-related documents. The majority of the documents date to the nineteenth century, although the eighteenth and twentieth centuries are also well represented. Some notable documents in the collection include: a book of auction records from 1837-1840 including sales of houses, ships, and slaves; an apothecary formula book; several examples of late eighteenth century legal papers; Civil War passes into Washington for the Leadbeater family; an Alexandria High School student exercise book from 1859-1863; apprenticeship indentures; an 1841 retrocession petition; and records of fires in the city from the 1930s and 1950s.
Arrangement
The collection is comprised of three series based on document size: 1) Letter size; 2) Legal size; 3) Oversize. Box numbers indicate the size of the documents, with 240 used for letter size, 240A for legal size, and 240B for oversize. Within the series arrangement is alphabetical by subject, and arrangement within subjects is also alphabetical.
Index Terms
Alexandria (Va.) - Commerce; Alexandria (Va.) - History
Contents List
  Series 1
- Letter size documents,1767-1974.
  - Account Books - Account of rents due estate of A.C. Cazenove, 1851-1853. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Armory Hall, 1882. 1 piece. Donated by Marvin Lee Steadman. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Bare to Hair, n.d. 1 piece. Donated by W.F. Smith. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Cotton factory, sale of,1869-1875. 10 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Dyson's Little Store, n.d. 4 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - George R. Hill & Co., Steam Bakers, price list, 1872. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Grammatical introduction to the English language, May 27, 1787. 1 piece and photocopy. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Janney & Co. Druggists, n.d. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Lyceum, vocal and instrument concert, ca. 1850. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Odd Fellows hall, Guy E. Miller speech, 1904. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Portner's Garden, 1875. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Mary G. Powell, History of Old Alexandria book flier, ca. 1928. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Stansbury & Bro., 1878. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Advertising - Joseph E. Willard, campaign for Governor, 1905. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Alexandria County - Health Department, health nuisance notice, 1919. 2 pieces. Donated in 1997. (Box 240-1)
  - Alexandria - History - Juvenile - A child's introduction to historic Alexandria,n.d. Envelope with 12 cards. Donated by Penny Morrill, 1997. (Box 240-1)
  - Alexandria - History - Juvenile Literature - Historic Alexandria Cook & Color,n.d. 1 coloring book. Donated by Penny Morrill, 1997. (Box 240-1)
  - Alexandria Theater - Sale of property statement, 1846. 2 pieces and photocopy. (Box 240-1)
  - Almanac - Cottom's Virginia and North Carolina Almanack, 1848. 1 leaf. Donated by W.F. Smith, 2003. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - Alexandria Building & Loan Association, passbook, 1924. 1 book. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - Alexandria National Bank, Isaac M. Whitestone passbook, 1922-1931. 1 book. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - Alexandria National Bank of Northern Virginia, annual service awards and dinner, 1977. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - Bank of Alexandria, stock certificates, 1793-1801. 5 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - Bank of Del Ray, checks and loans, 1921-1925. 6 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - Bank of Old Dominion, currency. 5 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - Exchange Bank of Virginia, Alexandria, promissory note, 1853. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - Farmer's Bank of Virginia, check, 1859. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - First National Bank, balance sheet, 1939. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Banks - First National Bank, checks and checkbook, 1870-1912. 4 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Beverley Hills - Beverley Hills Custom Built Homes, brochure, 1941. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-1)
  - Bicentennial - Alexandria postage stamp, 1949. 8 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Bicentennial - Alexandria Bicentennial Commission, events pamphlets and invitations, 1974. 7 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Bicentennial - First day covers envelopes, 1949. 4 pieces. Donated by Ray Rothgeb, 2000. (Box 240-1)
  - Bicentennial - Gunston Hall postage stamp sheet, 1958. 3 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Businesses - Alexandria Business Book, 1897. 1 book. (Box 240-1)
  - Businesses - Alexandria Fertilizer & Chemical Co., invoice to Bruce McIntosh, 1897. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Businesses - Alexandria Gas Works, invoice, 1858. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Businesses - Apartment rental receipt, 115 N. Fairfax Street, 1944. 2 pieces. (Box 240-1)
  - Businesses - Auction records, 1837-1840. Includes sales of lots, houses, ships, slaves, and other. 1 book. (Box 240-1)
  - Businesses - Robert Bell's Sons, advertising [missing, 5/12/2008] and valentine, n.d. 1 piece. (Box 240-1)
  - Businesses - W.H. Brown real estate account book, 1885-1918. 1 book. (Box 240-1)
  - Businesses - E.R. Boyer, Contractor, business card, ca. 1900. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Elias Edward Conner, miscellaneous business records, 1855-1873. 15 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - John T. Creighton, receipt, 1876. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - J. Dreifus & Co., 1864-1897. 17 pieces (photocopies). (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Fire Insurance Company of Alexandria, Virginia, stock certificates, 1857-1860. 2 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Flour inspection certificate, ca. 1820s. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - William Fowle, 1828-1860. 6 pieces and photocopies. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Benjamin Hallowell, receipt, 1824. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - George R. Hill Co., Fine Family Crackers, invoice, 1897. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - William Hudson, apothecary formula book, n.d. 1 book. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - John H. Ladd, 1818. 2 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - John Leadbeater, order, 1857. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Little River Turnpike Road Company, stocks, 1809-1849. 9 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Marine Insurance Company of Alexandria, stock, 1839. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - George Mason, page fragment re: tobacco,n.d. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Middle Turnpike Company, stock, 1831. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - E.J. Miller, receipt, 1867. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Northern Virginia Hotel Corporation, stocks, 1920s. 11 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Portner Brewing Company, receipt, 1901. Includes image of brewery. 1 piece. Donated by W.F. Smith. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Semmes & Lambert, postage stamp catalog, 1894. 1 piece. Purchased 1989. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Smoot & Co., miscellaneous receipts and Cazenove account, 1894-1896. Includes image of Smoot building. 5 pieces. Donated by W.F. Smith. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Edward Stabler, miscellaneous records, 1805-1823. 8 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Statement of the Commercial & Industrial Interests of the City of Alexandria, VA., With a Summary of Its History, 1904. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - J.H. Runnels, miscellaneous records, 1819. 8 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Virginia Shipbuilding Corporation, Rivet (Volume 1, Number 1), 1918. 1 newsletter. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Wise & Co., Insurance Agents, receipt and envelope from Cazenove account, 1899. 2 pieces. Donated by W.F. Smith. (Box 240-2)
  - Businesses - Woodward & Lothrop, Alexandria store opening, 1952. 2 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Canals - Alexandria Canal, 1821-1836. 3 pieces. (Box 240-2)
  - Cemeteries - Roll of Honor ... names of soldiers buried in the National Cemetery, Alexandria, Viginia, 1866. 1 item. (Box 240-2)
  - Cemeteries - Report of the Inspector of the National Cemeteries, U.S. Senate, 42nd Congress, 2nd Session, 1872. 1 item. (Box 240-2)
  - Chamber of Commece - Blue Book of Alexandria, 1952. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-2)
  - Chamber of Commerce - Gateway to the South, ca. 1920. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-2)
  - Civil War - Correspondence, unknown writer, 1864. 1 piece and transcription. (Box 240-2)
  - Civil War - Jeremiah Harwood, release from duty at the slave pen, 1866. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Civil War - Marshall House flagpole relics and Soldier's Pocket Book. 2 items. (Box 240-2)
  - Civil War - Military administration, 1864. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Civil War - Orders to General D. Ruggles at Corinth, Miss., 1862. 1 piece. (Box 240-2)
  - Coins and Currency - Confederate States of America. 30 pieces (paper). Donated by Treasury Department, 1913. (Box 240-2)
  - Coins and Currency - Confederate States of America. 9 pieces (paper). (Box 240-2)
  - Coins and Currency - Calendar coin, 1809. 1 artifact. (Box 240-2)
  - Coins and Currency - Colonial American. 5 pieces (paper). Donated by Margery Hall Fawcett in memory of Mary Lloyd Fawcett, 1991. (Box 240-2)
  - Communication - Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company, brochure about Alexandria, 1940. 1 brochure. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Adam, Mary, 1847. 1 piece. Gift of the Sully Foundation, 1979. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Barger, Mary Beth, 1988. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Barrett, Kate Waller, letter from Theodore Roosevelt, 1903. 1 piece. Gift of J. Alfriend, 1996. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Barton, Benjamin, 1860. 2 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Bitting, C.C. to Sidney Hayden, 1865. 2 pieces (photocopies). (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Brooks, C.C., postcard, 1909. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Brown, W. Barrett, 1968. 4 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Burke, John W. to Edward Turner, 1873. 1 piece. Purchased in 1990. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Cass, Lewis to Bernard Hooe, Mayor, 1835. 1 piece. Donated by William Glasgow and Milton Park Penn. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Caton, James R., 1901. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Cazenove, Anthony W., 1826. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Claughton, Hiram O., 1875. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Coleman, George, 1828. 1 piece. Purchased in 1991. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Composition on vacation, unsigned and undated. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Cooper, Samuel, re: 60th Virginia Regiment, 1861. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Crease, J.H., 1837. 1 piece (photocopy). (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Cullum, George, re: construction of Fort Sumter, 1856. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Custis, George Washington Parke, 1853. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Edward ? to Mrs. Jno. B. Daingerfield from Capon Springs and Baths, 1881. 2 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Danforth, T., 1850. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Douglas, Henry H., 1968-1973. 8 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Hamilton, A., 1853. 3 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Hooe, R.W. to General Ruggles, November 13, 1865. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Hull, Hannah, 1863. 1 piece. Purchased in 1992. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Johns, John, Rev., 1852?. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Johnson, J.B., 1867. 1 piece. Donated by William Glasgow and Milton Park Penn. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Kummer, Mary C. to Fanny, August 10,1847. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Lee family, 1805-1806. 3 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Lee, Cassius F., 1860. 2 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Lee, Mary Anna Randolph Custis, 1865-1873. 13 pieces and photocopies. Donated by Col. Edgar Snowden IV and Julia Snowden Neumeyer, 1985. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Lee, Robert Edward, 1868. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Lee, Robert E., Jr. to Green & Bro., 1872. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Lyceum(?), n.d. Names: Miller, Duncan, Carne, et al. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Martin, Thomas S. to T.R. Fones, February 1, 1911. 2 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Maryland Line Confederate Soldiers' Home, 1911. 2 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - McClellan, George B., re: Illinois Central Railroad, 1859. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - McGroarty, William Buckner, 1930s. 22 pieces (photocopies). (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Meigs, Montgomery C., re: Capitol Extension, 1856. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Page, William, 1843. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Phillips, S.C., 1830. 1 piece. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Pierson, Mr. from John Mason, 1885. 3 pieces and photocopies. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Porterfield, M., ca. 1850. 3 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Powell, Levin to son Burr, re: death of George Washington, 1799. 2 pieces. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1953. 5 pieces. Donated by Alexandria League of Women Voters, 2000. (Box 240-3)
  - Correspondence - Sam to Ruth, 1896. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Semmes, Cora, 1852. 2 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Shepard, William B., 1836. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Smith, F.L. from Bank of Commerce, Richmond, 1874. 2 pieces. Donated in 2000. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Smith, Francis L., re: Constitutional Convention, 1901. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Smoot, John B. to Adelaide, 1855-1865. 8 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Smoot, John B. to his father, 1865. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Smoot, W.A. from Thoroughfare Mills, 1879. 1 piece. Donated by W.F. Smith, 2003. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Sawyer, Sarah W., 1863. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Southerland, E.G., 1847. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Stabler, E.H. to John Stabler, 1852. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Stearns, Ashael to John Lloyd, 1821. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Stern, J.L, 1898. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Stone, Margaret, 1840. 2 pieces with photocoies and transcript. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Stuart, James E.B. [subject] re: Cheyenne Expedition and promotion, 1857-1860. 3 pieces. Donated by Virginia Waller Stuart Davis, 1985. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Thomson, James M., 1957. 2 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - United States Military Telegraph draft to Captain P.P. Pitkin, 1864. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Veitch, P. to John Ambler, 1809. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Vowell, Thomas, 1838. 1 piece. Gift of Mr. Beverly H. Harris. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Walsh, Richard to Samuel Marsteller, 1811. 1 piece. Purchased 1991. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Wilson, Gus V. to John McCormick, 1861. 1 piece and transcription. (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Yeaton, Louisa Toscan, 1818. 1 piece (photocopy). (Box 240-4)
  - Correspondence - Wignell, Anne Warren, 1804. 4 pieces (photocopies). (Box 240-4)
  - Dances - Invitation, First Hop of the Season, 1867. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Diaries - Davy, Thomas, 1818-1826, transcript. 16 pages. Donated by Jean Campbell Roberts Harris, 1989. (Box 240-4)
  - Diaries - Holden, George, Co. C., 1st Maine re: end of Civil War, 1865. 1 book. (Box 240-4)
  - Diaries - Lee, Ann Matilda, copybook, ca. 1824. 1 book and 15 pages. (Box 240-4)
  - Diseases - Yellow fever epidemic in Alexandria, 1803. 3 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Elections - Memorial from Electors of Elections in Alexandria, VA, March 7, 1867. 2 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - George Washington Bicentennial - Programs. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-4)
  - HABS - Bailey, Worth. 5 miscellaneous field notebooks. 5 booklets. (Box 240-4)
  - Harbor - U.S. House of Representatives, miscellaneous reports, 1903-1908. 9 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Arlington House, seat of G.W.P. Custis, Esq. article by Benson Lossing in Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1853. 1 magazine. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Cameron Street, 508, correspondence, 1932-1937. 10 pieces. Donated in 1997. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Carlyle House, flier, ca. 1930. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Carlyle House, opening, Northern Virginia Regional Park Authority, 1976. 5 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Colross, history, Kindly but Alien Hands, n.d. 33 pages. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Custom House, miscellaneous correspondence, 1867-1882. 2 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - "Furnishings of ... Gadsby's Tavern, Alexandria, VA." Parke-Bernet auction catalog, 1938. 1 piece. Donated in 2001. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Gadsby's Tavern, history by Charles H. Callahan, ca. 1940. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Lloyd House, Historic American Buildings Survey certificate. 2 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Lyceum Fair Journal, 1889. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Prince Street, 504, Civil War confiscation. 3 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Ramsay House, Restoration Association pamphlet, 1944 and dedication program, 1956. 2 pamphlets. (Box 240-4)
  - Historic Buildings - Washington's Town House, 508 Cameron Street. 7 pieces. Donated by Stuart E. Brown,Jr., 1998. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Appointment of Joseph Broders, Police Constable, 1825. 1 piece and photocopy of transcript. Gift of Timothy Callahan, 1998. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Hunter, John, petition re: Col. John FitzGerald, 1803. 2 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Bill of sale, lot at southeast corner of Queen and Alfred Streets, 1852. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Custis, G.W.P., Custis's Exr. vs. Lee and others, Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Coates, Thomas H., deed, lots 27-29 in Del Ray, 1924. 2 pieces. Donated in 1997. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - First National Bank of Alexandria vs. Alexander Turnbull, et. al., 1871. 3 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Gadsby, John, promissory note from W. Hopkins, 1807. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - lee, Richard Henry, promissory note to Samuel Carr, 1825. 1 piece. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Luckett, Horace, financial papers, 1818-1819. 2 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Marshall, John vs. Phillip Hunt, 1767. 5 pieces. (Box 240-4)
  - Legal Papers - Petition of William Ladd, 1812. 2 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Legal Papers - Ramsay, Edward, summons to court, 1787. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Legal Papers - Washington, Alexandria & Georgetown Railroad vs. Catherine Brown, 1868-1873. 3 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Libraries - Correspondence, New York Public Library director to Alexandria Library, 1937. 2 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Lottery - Alexandria Lottery, 1847. 6 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Magazines - Appleton's Magazine, July 1906. 1 magazine. (Box 240-5)
  - Magazines - Century Magazine, November 1887. 1 magazine. (Box 240-5)
  - Magazines - New England Magazine, November 1902. 1 magazine. (Box 240-5)
  - Magazines - The Virginia Churchman, June 1957. 1 magazine. (Box 240-5)
  - Mayors - Anti-Confederate poem by Mayor Charles Wore, n.d. 1 piece. Purchased in 1997. (Box 240-5)
  - Mayors - William N. Berkley, appointment, April 11, 1868. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Mayors - Report of the Mayor, 26th Congress, 1st Session, 1840. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Bird's Eye View of Alexandria, VA, souvenir envelopes, n.d. 7 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - George Washington birthday events. 5 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Grover Cleveland, Inaugural Commemorative, 1885. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Confederate Memorial Day poems. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Confederate States of America, Treasurer's Office stationery. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Illustrated Southern Almanac, 1893. 1 book. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Jamestown, VA Tercentennial, souvenir guide, 1907. 1 book. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Leadbeater Family, passes to Washington, 1862-1863. 4 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Military passes, 1860s. 3 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - My Parole, by an Old Soldier, 1865. 1 piece. Donated by W.F. Smith. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Orange & Alexandria Railroad Company, envelope, ca. 1860. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Robert E. Lee Camp, Confederate Veterans, annual reunion, 1897. 2 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Robert E. Lee Camp, Confederate Veterans, letterhead. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Ration books and tokens, 1945. 18 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Confederate States of America, War Department stationery. 2 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Virginia Shipbuilding Corporation, invitation to launch of S.S. Clemence C. Morse, January 10, 1920. 1 piece. Donated by William F. Smith, 2003. (Box 240-5)
  - Memorabilia - Young Men's Senate, 1909. 1 piece. Donated by Howard W. Smith. (Box 240-5)
  - Mount Vernon Memorial Highway - "National Road from the Aqueduct Bridge ...," U.S. House of Representativese, 1890. 10 pages from book. (Box 240-5)
  - Music - fliers for performances of Gilbert & Sullivan's Patience and Pirates of Penzance (photocopies); Song on the Death of Col. Ellsworth, 1861. 3 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Music - Lannon's Opera House, 1894-1897. 2 pieces (photocopies). (Box 240-5)
  - Music - Opera House program, 1897. 1 piece (photocopy). (Box 240-5)
  - Music - Recital of Miss Ida Ullman and Pupils, 1922. 1 piece (photocopy). (Box 240-5)
  - Music - Sarepta Hall program, 1874. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - New Alexandria - Promotional brochure, 1893. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-5)
  - Northern Virginia Bureau - The Hills of Northern Virginia, ca. 1920. 1 book. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alcoholics Anonymous, The Eye Opener. 1 book. Donated by J. Gott. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Association Yearbooks, 1967-1979. 3 pamphlets. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Business & Professional Women's Club, 1924. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Community Chest. 2 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Hospital, Board of Lady Managers pamphlets, 1950s-1980s. 2 pamphlets. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Host Lions Club, 40th Anniversary Charter Night, 1973. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Infirmary, annual report, 1898. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Library Company, annual lecture programs, 1958-1974. 8 pieces. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Police Association, recruitment banquet, 1977. 1 pamphlet. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Rotary Club, program, January 31, 1978. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Alexandria Washington Lodge No. 22, A.F.&A.M., Songster. 1 piece. (Box 240-5)
  - Organizations - Anne Lee Memorial Home for the Aged, directory of officers, n.d. 1 booklet. (Box 240-5)